DR SHAHIDA AZIZ

Gujrat , Pakistan · +92334-4720810 <u>drshahidaaziz@gmail.com</u>

Consultant Gynecologist and Obstetrician

FCPS Consultant gynecologist with 10+ years of extensive academic and clinical experience in the diagnosis and treatment of a wide range of women's diseases, well trained in performing gynecologic surgeries, including diagnostic and emergency procedures.

EXPERIENCE

FEBUARARY 2020 – PRESENT

CONSULTANT GYNECOLOGIST, GOVERNMENT OF PUNJAB, GUJRAT, PAKISTAN

- Manage Patient in Out Patient, Emergency, In-Patient and Labour Room.
- Assess, diagnose, and treat female reproductive disorders, including abnormal bleeding and irregular menstrual periods, endometriosis, genital infections, ovarian cysts, breast abnormalities, and several other conditions concerning the female reproductive system
- Provide antenatal Care and Handle high risk pregnancies with diabetes, hypertension, hypothyroidism, hyperthyroidism, connective tissue disorders, APLA syndrome, anomalous baby and IUGR.

NOVEMBER 2018 – FEBUARARY 2020

MEDICAL OFFICER GYNECOLOGY, GOVERNMENT OF PUNJAB, GUJRANWALA,

Manage patient in outpatient, emergency, in-patient and labour room.

AUGUST 2017 – NOVEMBER 2018

SENIOR REGISTRAR GYNECOLOGIST, RAFIQ ANWAR MEMORIAL HOSPITAL, GUJRANWALA, PAKISTAN

- Provide medical attention for women during menstrual periods, conception, pregnancy, and birth and post-partum stages.
- Perform SVD, Caesarean Section, Laparotomy, Hysterectomy and Minor Gynaecological surgeries in operation theatre.

FEBUARARY 2013 – DECEMBER 2014

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR- FRONTIER MEDICAL/DENTAL COLLEGE

Teaching a requisite number of classes, providing guidance and supervision to graduate students.

DECEMBER 2006 – JANUARY 2011

POSTGRADUATE TRAINEE/RESIDENT, NISHTAR HOSPITAL, MULTAN, PAKISTAN

- Trainee in gynecology obstetrics along with medicine and radiology rotation
- Trained to manage gyne/obs patients in Outdoor, Emergency, Inpatient and Labour Room.

JANUARY 2005 – JANUARY 2006

HOUSE OFFICER, KHYBER TEACHING HOSPITAL, PESHAWER, PAKISTAN

EDUCATION

2013

FCPS IN GYNECOLOGY AND OBSTETRICS, CPSP

Fellowship in Gynecology and Obstetrics from College of Physician and Surgeons, Pakistan.

2004

M.B; B.S, KHYBER MEDICAL COLLEGE, PESHAWER, PAKISTAN.

Bachelor of Medicine And Bachelor of Surgery.

LANGUAGES

Urdu English Punjabi Pashto Arabic (Reading Only)

COURSES / WORKSHOPS

- o Professional Ethics Workshop.
- Teaching methodology workshop.
- Lecture and problem-based learning.

PUBLICATIONS

- Outcome of trial of labour with Previous-1 Caesarean Section, published in Medical Forum Monthly/Volume.25/Number 03-March 2014
- Gestational Diabetes in Patients with Obesity, published in Medical Forum Monthly/Volume.25/Number 08-August 2014

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATION

- PMC PAKISTAN MEDICAL COMMISSION 11758-N
- CPSP COLLEGE OF PHYSICIANS AND SURGEONS PAKISTAN OBG-13-14038

SKILLS

- Excellent social, interpersonal and communication skills to interact with patients and hospital staff.
- Strong ability to work under extreme pressure of childbirth and delivery procedures.
- Unfailing flexibility and adaptability
- Problem-solving and critical thinking skills
- Attention to detail
- Excellent bedside manner.
- Good computer skills